export const Questions10 = 
[
    {
        "question": "What is a fundamental characteristic of human communication?",
        "optionA": "It is a static process.",
        "optionB": "It is always reversible.",
        "optionC": "It is dynamic and continuous.",
        "optionD": "It only involves verbal messages.",
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a component of the communication process?",
        "optionA": "Stimulus",
        "optionB": "Sender/Encoder",
        "optionC": "Feedback",
        "optionD": "Audience",
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of communication is described as 'talking to oneself using internal vocalisation or reflective thinking'?",
        "optionA": "Interpersonal Communication",
        "optionB": "Group Communication",
        "optionC": "Intrapersonal Communication",
        "optionD": "Public Communication",
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which non-verbal communication channel involves the study of body movements and gestures?",
        "optionA": "Proxemics",
        "optionB": "Kinesics",
        "optionC": "Paravocalics",
        "optionD": "Haptics",
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one disadvantage of written communication?",
        "optionA": "It lacks permanence.",
        "optionB": "It requires literacy in the language of writing.",
        "optionC": "It provides immediate feedback.",
        "optionD": "It is easily deniable.",
        "answer": "B"
    },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for communication that involves a person talking to themselves, which influences their views and self-perception?",
            "optionA": "Interpersonal Communication",
            "optionB": "Group Communication",
            "optionC": "Mass Communication",
            "optionD": "Intrapersonal Communication",
            "answer": "D"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following types of noise refers to problems with the mechanical quality of a communication channel, such as a faulty signal or poor-quality print?",
            "optionA": "Psychological Noise",
            "optionB": "Channel Noise",
            "optionC": "Linguistic Noise",
            "optionD": "Semantic Noise",
            "answer": "B"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which type of communication does a person or group send messages to a large and heterogeneous audience using technological channels?",
            "optionA": "Interpersonal Communication",
            "optionB": "Organisational Communication",
            "optionC": "Public or Mass Communication",
            "optionD": "Group Communication",
            "answer": "C"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does 'paravocalics' refer to in non-verbal communication?",
            "optionA": "The use of touch to communicate",
            "optionB": "The use of facial expressions and body movements",
            "optionC": "Vocal attributes such as pitch and volume",
            "optionD": "The use of space to communicate",
            "answer": "C"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which characteristic of human language allows people to discuss abstract issues and convey complex ideas, such as future events or hypothetical situations?",
            "optionA": "Arbitrary",
            "optionB": "Dynamic",
            "optionC": "Learned",
            "optionD": "Creative",
            "answer": "D"
        },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following attributes is central to human language?",
                "optionA": "Universality",
                "optionB": "Simplicity",
                "optionC": "Static Nature",
                "optionD": "Uniformity",
                "answer": "A"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does phonology study in the context of language?",
                "optionA": "Word Formation",
                "optionB": "Sentence Structure",
                "optionC": "Speech Sounds",
                "optionD": "Grammar Rules",
                "answer": "C"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which African language variant is known as a simplified language used for trade?",
                "optionA": "Creole",
                "optionB": "Pidgin",
                "optionC": "Swahili",
                "optionD": "Zulu",
                "answer": "B"
            },
            {
                "question": "In which aspect of language does morphology focus?",
                "optionA": "Sound Patterns",
                "optionB": "Word Formation",
                "optionC": "Sentence Construction",
                "optionD": "Meaning of Words",
                "answer": "B"
            },
            {
                "question": "What term is used to describe the study of how words are arranged to form phrases and clauses?",
                "optionA": "Phonology",
                "optionB": "Morphology",
                "optionC": "Syntax",
                "optionD": "Semantics",
                "answer": "C"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does the mass media primarily aim to do in terms of cultural promotion?",
                "optionA": "Create New Cultures",
                "optionB": "Disregard Indigenous Cultures",
                "optionC": "Promote Both Indigenous and Foreign Cultures",
                "optionD": "Focus Solely on Foreign Cultures",
                "answer": "C"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a traditional African communication method?",
                "optionA": "Talking Drum",
                "optionB": "Xylophone",
                "optionC": "Radio Broadcast",
                "optionD": "Masquerade",
                "answer": "C"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the role of visual communication in African culture?",
                "optionA": "To Convey Historical Events",
                "optionB": "To Communicate Ethnic and Cultural Identity",
                "optionC": "To Promote Modern Technology",
                "optionD": "To Enhance Academic Learning",
                "answer": "B"
            },
            {
                "question": "In African communication systems, what does 'extra-mundane' communication refer to?",
                "optionA": "Everyday Conversations",
                "optionB": "Spiritual and Ritual Communication",
                "optionC": "Written Documents",
                "optionD": "Visual Symbols",
                "answer": "B"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is a benefit of the internet for youth in Africa?",
                "optionA": "Access to Outdated Information",
                "optionB": "Improvement in Language Skills",
                "optionC": "Increase in Cultural Homogeneity",
                "optionD": "Decrease in Educational Resources",
                "answer": "B"
            }
]
